어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
지라이얀은 무사시에게 히미코가 시라누이 일족의 여왕이라고 말했다. 그러나 믿기지 않는 일이었다.
Jiraiyan told Musashi that Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan. But he couldn't believe that.
쥬베의 조사로 시라누이 일족은 불의 나라의 자손이라는 것을 알게 됐다.
By Jube's investigation, they found out that Shiranui Clan is the descendants of the Fire Country.
그러나 거기서 가엔마에게 당해, 아차하며 위기에 빠졌다.
But by Gaenma's attack, they fell into a crisis in an instant.
그 혼잡한 틈을 타서 무사시는 변장해 시라누이 일족으로 잠입한다.
Using that chaotic moment, Musashi disguises himself as Shiranui and infiltrates to them.
불의 나라의 여왕
히미코이오
The Queen of the Fire Country
Himiko
정지!
Stop!
어이, 조심해라!
Hey, be careful!
아, 미안하오.
I'm sorry-dasu.
전원 모였는가!
Are everyone here?
그럼 사쿠라라고 하면?
Then, what follows the word Sakura?
-사쿠라지마!
-사쿠마모찌!
-Sakurajima!
-Sakuramochi!
사, 사쿠라모찌?
S- Sakuramochi?
아, 아니, 사쿠라모찌는 맛있소.
Err, Sakuramochi is tasty-dasu.
나 정말 좋아하오!
I love it-dasu!
암호가 다르다!
Your password is different!
아, 아니, 배가 고파서 절로 새어나왔소.
Well, that's, I was too hungry and it came out-dasu!
미안하오, 미안하오.
Sorry-dasu, sorry-dasu!
사쿠라라고 하면 사쿠라지마이오!
Sakura means Sakurajima-dasu!
뭐, 됐다! 우리는 다음 임무를 위해 즉시 본거지 사쿠라지마에 들어간다!
Well, good enough! We're returning to our base Sakurajima right away, for our next mission!
와라!
Come!
잘 됐소. 말 안해도 계속하오!
That's a relief-dasu. Then let me continue-dasu!
코지로.
Kojirō.
센히메 님. 전 언제라도 갈 수 있습니다.
Senhime. I'm prepared as always.
나도 준비 OK야.
I'm ready, too.
쥬베!
Jube!
시라누이 일족 따위 이 언월도로 엉망진창으로 만들어 주겠어!
I'll use my halberd to get rid of those Shiranuis!
센히메 님.
Senhime.
그냥 하는 말이지만, 공주님은 가지 말고 여기서 기다리시는 게...
I was thinking that you should wait here, instead of going...
저도 그렇게 말씀드리고 싶었습니다만...
I wanted to say that too, but...
그 덜렁쇠 멍청이 무사시는 분명 시라누이 일족에 숨어들어가 사쿠라지마에 간 게 뻔해.
That birdbrain fool Musashi must be heading to Sakurajima, smuggled into Shiranuis.
그렇습니다. 그러니까 여긴...
I agree. That's why you should...
그러니까, 그 덜렁쇠 멍청이 단고쟁이를 구하기 위해 우리가 갈 수밖에 없잖아?
That's why we all should go together to rescue that birdbrain fool by marching in!
그러니까, 저희가...
I'm saying that we'll...
그래. 우리가 무사시를 구하러 가는 거야.
Yes. We are going to rescue Musashi.
기다려라, 무사시! 죽으면 안 된다! 살아! 살아남아!
Wait for us, Musashi! Do not die! Live! Survive!
지팡구 제일의 무예가의 꿈을 버리면 안 돼, 무사시!
Never give up on your dream of becoming the number one martial artist of Jipangu, Musashi!
센히메 님은 말해도 안 듣는 분이라서...
Senhime never listens to whoever it is...
자, 알겠냐! 꼭 간다! 우리, 그리고 나 너 따라간다! 무사시! 기다려!
Never forget that we're going for you! Everyone are going for you! Musashi! Just you wait for us!
공주님은 분명 말띠.
She was born in the Year of the Horse.
그렇군요. 그래서 말처럼 날뛰시는군요.
I see. That's why she's bucking like a horse.
여러분, 준비는 되셨습니까.
Everyone, are you ready?
아, 완전히!
Yeah, completely!
좋소.
Great.
그럼 출발하오.
Then let's go-gowasu.
좋아! 시라누이 일족의 본거지에 자, 가자!
Alright! We're going to the base of Shiranui Clan, starting now!
어라? 우리 사쿠라지마에 가는 것 아니었소? 왜 배에 안 타오?
Huh? Weren't we going to Sakurajima-dasu? Why aren't we riding boat-dasu?
너 신입이냐?
Are you a newcomer?
어, 저, 그렇소. 나 아직 수습 기간이어서...
Uh, well, that's right-dasu. I'm still learning things-dasu...
그, 그렇소! 나 계속 길에서 딴짓해서 몰랐소!
Y- yeah-dasu! I didn't realize because I was loitering on the way-dasu!
서둘러!
Hurry!
이야, 눈 깜짝할 새에 안 보이게 되었소.
Woah, it's gone in a blink of a eye-dasu!
서두르랬지!
I told you to hurry!
이제 돌아갈 수 없게 되었소.
I can't go back anymore-dasu.
사쿠라지마 속에 이런 장치가 있었소...
I never knew there was this kind of device in Sakurajima-dasu...
그리고 시라누이 일족의 본거지.
And the base of Shiranui Clan.
타오르오!
It's burning-dasu!
뭣이오?
What is it-dasu?
아, 딱히.
Uh, nothing.
히미코 님!
Lord Himiko!
지라이얀이 말한 건 사실이었소.
What Jiraiyan said was true-dasu.
히미코 씨가 시라누이 일족의 여왕이었다니...
I never thought Ms. Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan...
제군! 때는 왔다.
Everyone! The time has come.
우리 시라누이 일족을 부흥할 때가! 지금 이 땅에!
The time to revive Shiranui Clan, on this ground!
예, 여왕님!
Yessir, your majesty!
여왕님!
Your majesty!
우리 시라누이 일족은 지금에서 거슬러 올라가길 2000년. 불의 나라의 혈족으로서 번영을 바라며 일하고 있었다.
We, Shiranui Clan, began 2,000 years ago, as one blood of the Fire Country, working hard for prosperity.
그러나 그 번영은 잠시였다.
But that prosperity was short.
그 이래, 우리 불의 나라의 자들은 떠돌이 생활을 해왔을 뿐이었다.
Ever since then, people of the Fire Country has been roaming.
그러나 고절! 고절 2000년! 지금이야말로 우리 시라누이 일족의 손에 돈으로는 얻을 수 없는 번영을 되찾을 때입니다!
But we had unswerving determination for 2,000 years!
Now is the time to take back the prosperity that we cannot buy with money to us, Shiranui Clan!
이 손으로 약속된 번영의 불의 나라를 재건하는 것입니다.
We will rebuild the Fire Country of promised prosperity by our own hands.
그걸 위해서는 이 지팡구 곡을 우리 수중에!
For that, we have to take Jipangu State into our hands!
예! 히미코 여왕님! 히미코 여왕님!
Yessir! Queen Himiko! Queen Himiko!
이, 이건 대단한 음모이오.
T- this is a serious conspiracy-dasu!
제군. 잘 들어라. 우리 부흥을 위해 새로운 동료가 힘을 빌려주게 되었다.
Listen to me, everyone. A new comrade is going to help us for our revival.
자, 한조 님.
Mr. Hanzo.
에, 한조!?
Wha- Hanzo!?
하, 한조!
H- Hanzo!
나 한조는 전력을 다해 불의 나라 재건을 돕겠다.
I, Hanzo will do everything I can to help the revival of the Fire Country.
역시 한조가 히미코하고...
I knew that Hanzo and Himiko were...
제군! 우리 목적을 달성하기 위해서는 먼저 시라누이 일족이 무장봉기하고 지팡구국을 전복시켜야 한다.
Everyone! For our objective, Shiranui must move first and do an armed uprising to overthrow Jipangu State.
시라누이 일족에 한조가 가세했다니 큰일이오!
This really is serious, for that Hanzo to join forces with Shiranui Clan-dasu!
지팡국을 점령한 새벽에는 사람들을 걸레짝인 양 부려
On the dawn of occupying Jipangu State, we will make people drudge
지금까지의 원한을 풀고 히미코 여왕 아래서 시라누이 일족의 염원, 불의 나라를 장렬히 재건할 것이다.
to pay off old scores, and under the ruling of Queen Himiko,
we will heroically achieve our long-cherished desire of reviving the Fire Country
예!
Yessir!
정말 큰일났소.
This is really bad-dasu.
이건 깊이 개입하지 않는 게 나을 것 같다.
I should not be deeply involved in this.
숨어 있어!
Stay put!
히미코 님도 대단한 분이시다.
Lord Himiko is a great person.
그, 그렇소.
T- that's true-dasu.
~소?
dasu?
얘 설마... 무사시?
Is this guy Musashi!?
제군! 나와 한조에게 승리의 맹새를!
Everyone! Make an oath of victory to Hanzo and me!
예! 히미코 여왕님! 예! 한조 님!
Yessir! Queen Himiko! Yesser! Mr. Hanzo!
흥. 이 정도의 연설으로 참으로 불처럼 타오른다니 단순한 놈들이구나.
Hmph. They're burning up just like fire, only because of a speech of this simplicity? What a simple-minded fools.
고개 숙여! 들킨다, 무사시!
Lower your head! You're standing out, Musashi!
이건 어서 모두에게 알려야 하오!
I have to let everyone know about this as soon as possible-dasu!
거기 너 어디 가나!
Where are you going!?
아, 아, 그게, 저... 왠지 흥분해서 오줌싸고 싶어졌소.
Er, well, that's, um... I was so excited that I now want to pee-dasu.
~소?
dasu?
아니아니아니, 가는 걸세다.
Nonono, I'm going-gowasu.
바보 자식.
You fool...
얼굴을 보여라!
Show your face!
아, 아니, 보일 정도의 얼굴은 아니오.
N- no, this isn't a face worth being shown-dasu.
아니라, 아닌걸세다!
Nono, gowasu!
아! 그만하시는 걸세다!
Ahh! Stop it-gowasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
아니오! 인 걸세다! 나, 무사시가 아닌 걸세다!
No-dasu! -gowasu! I'm not Musashi-gowasu!
그래그래그래, 그 무사시라는 자하고 딱 닮게 흉내내고 있었는데 그렇게 불리다니 잘 되는가 보구려.
Rightrightright, I was imitating that Musashi guy, but to be called as Musashi, I must be doing well-gowasu!
거기까지 들킨 주제에 뭔 변명이야! 어서 도망쳐!
No excuse will get you out of that situation! Just run!
호, 넌 무사시가 아니라는 거냐? 그럼 이걸 받아 봐라!
Oh, you're claiming that you're not Musashi? Then take this!
바보.
Idiot!
만두를 주다니 감사하오! 맛있소!
Thank you for the dumpling-dasu! Tasty!
저 더러운 식탐을 보아하니, 저 놈은 분명히 무사시다!
Judging from the filthiness of that gluttony, that guy really is Musashi!
저런...
Oh no...
멍청한 무사시.
Stupid Musashi.
만두를 위해 목숨을 내던졌냐, 무사시! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Did you really give up your life for that dumplings, Musashi!? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
무사시는 저기에.
Musashi is over there.
예. 다만, 센히메 님, 지금 다시 한번 생각을.
Yes. But, Senhime, please think one more time before we go.
제게 두 말은 없습니다.
I keep my word.
출발하면 못 돌아올 지도 모르오.
We might not be able to get back once we leave-gowasu.
예. 저는 매일매일을 말뚝 없는 듯 전력을 다해 살고 있습니다. 그러니까... 미련이 남는 건 하나도 없습니다.
Yes, but I'm living to my best everyday as if there is no tomorrow. That's why I do not have any lingering attachment.
그러고 보니 하나 미련이 있습니다.
Thinking about it, I have one attachment.
공주님, 그건 무엇입니까?
Princess, what is that?
남자 못 찾은 거!
I couldn't find a good male!
흥. 들킨 이상 어쩔 수 없소!
Hmph! You found me out, and then I'm going to deal with it-dasu!
무사시. 너 살아 있었구나!
Musashi! You were alive!
흥! 살아 돌아왔소!
Hmph! I revived-dasu!
잘도 날 속였겠소, 히미코!
You dared to deceive me-dasu, Himiko!
속은 네가 바보다.
It means that you're a fool.
한번 죽었어도 그 멍청한 건 안 고쳐졌나 보구나.
It seems that your foolishness has not been fixed even after dying once.
뻔뻔스레 시라누이의 본거지에 들어오다니 말이다!
How dare you sneak into the base of Shiranui unconcernedly!
그 대담무쌍한 점이 내 성격이오!
That dauntlessness is my personality-dasu!
지껄이지 마라, 꼬맹아!
Do not babble, you brat!
젠장!
Damn!
이번에야말로 저 세상에 되돌려 보내 주겠다!
I will send you back to that world this time!
뭣이!?
What!?
지라이얀!
Jiraiyan!
무사시!
Musashi!
지라이얀, 미안하오. 역시 히미코는 시라누이 일족의 여왕이었소.
I'm sorry-dasu, Jiraiyan. That Himiko really was the queen of Shiranui-dasu.
이제 됐으니까 어쨌든 도망쳐!
Forget about that; just run away!
내가 상대해 주겠소!
I'll face them-dasu!
죽여라! 죽여!
Kill him! Kill!
지라이얀, 오랜만이다!
Jiraiyan, it's been a while!
너 왜 이런 곳에?
Why are you here?
그건 내가 할 말이다! 왜 네가 시라누이하고!
That's my line! Why are you with Shiranui?
답은 곧 알게 될 테다. 우리에게 칼을 든 자에게는 죽음만이 있을 뿐! 찾을 수고도 덜었다!
You'll know why soon. Only death waits whoever stands in our way! You showed yourself so that we won't have to find you!
이 놈은 내가 처리한다.
I'll deal with him.
너 따위가 날 이길 수 있을 리가 없다!
It is impossible for you to defeat me!
뭣이!?
What!?
누구이오!?
Who was that!?
겐바, 텐젠, 가엔마의 원수는 이 진나이가 갚겠다.
I, Jinnai, will pay back the resentment of Genba, Tenzen, and Gaenma!
어라!?
Huh!?
시라누이 요술, 불덩어리 돌팔매!
Shiranui Magic, Fireball Throwing Stone!
젠장!
Damn!
거기까지구나.
That's as far as you go.
케로키치!
Kerokichi!
무사시! 잘 달아나라!
Musashi! Please escape safely!
이제 끝이구나, 무사시!
Your life is over, Musashi!
무념이오.
How regretful-dasu.
멈추십시오.
Stop.
히미코 여왕님.
Lord Queen Himiko!
그 자는 제가 처리하겠습니다.
I will take care of that guy.
무사시 씨, 당신은 오해하고 있습니다.
Mr. Musashi, you are misunderstanding.
오해?
Misunderstand?
오해라니 뭔 소리이오!
What do you mean by misunderstanding-dasu!?
나는 적이 아닙니다.
I am not your enemy.
뭣이오? 아니아니아니아니, 속지 않소! 그런 소리를 해서 날 죽일 생각이오!
What-dasu? Nononono, I won't get deceived-dasu! You're trying to kill me again by saying that-dasu!
저는 그런 일은 하지 않습니다.
I don't do that.
이전에 무사시 씨가 저를 보고 어머님 같다고 말씀하셨죠?
Mr. Musashi, you told me that I'm just like your mother, right?
아파, 아파!
It hurts, it hurts!
엄마, 아파, 엄마, 아파!
Mommy, it hurts! Mommy, it hurts!
왜 그러니, 무사시.
What's wrong, Musashi?
おいら、転んじゃったの。
あら、痛かったわね。痛いの痛いの飛んで行け！
ほら！もう大丈夫でしょう？
うん、もう痛くない。
母ちゃん。
그랬었소.
That's true-dasu.
그런 분을 죽이다니.
I can't kill someone like that.
자, 배고프죠? 어서 드세요.
I know you're hungry. Please eat.
아, 감사하오! 역시 히미코 씨는 친절하오!
Thank you-dasu! I knew that you really are kind-dasu!
맛있소, 맛있소, 맛있소! 정말 맛있소, 맛있소, 맛있소!
Tasty, tasty, tasty-dasu! It's really tasty, tasty, tasty-dasu!
자, 기분 좋아지셨죠, 무사시?
Do you feel happy, Musashi?
네...
Yes...
자, 예쁜 꽃이 보이죠?
Can you see a beautiful flower?
네...
Yes...
몇 개?
How many?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
불꽃이 사라지면 무사시는 제 것. 알겠어요?
When the flames disappear, Musashi is mine. Understand?
네이오.
Yes-dasu.
무사시? 무사시?
Musashi? Musashi?
네이오.
Yes-dasu.
무사시, 제가 말하는 것은 무엇이든 들으세요.
Musashi. Listen to whatever I say.
네. 무사시는 히미코 여왕님이 말씀하시는 것은 무엇이든 듣소.
Yessir. Musashi will listen to whatever Lord Queen Himiko says-dasu.
당신은 아직 많이 일해야 할 것입니다. 기껏 살아 돌아오셨으니.
You will work for me much more from now on, since you managed to revive at great pains.
네. 무사시는 기껏 살아 돌아왔으니 히미코 여왕님을 위해 일하오.
Yessir. Since Musashi managed to revive at great pains, he will work for Lord Queen Himiko-dasu.
좋아.
Good.
여기는 벌써 시라누이의 본거지. 언제 적이 덮쳐들지 모릅니다.
We're already at the base of Shiranui. The enemy can come to attack us without notice.
방심은 금물이오.
Do not let your guards down-gowasu.
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시! 무사했구나!
Musashi! You're safe!
왜 그러나, 시로!
What's wrong, Shiro?
죽여라. 죽여라.
Kill. Kill.
무사시!
Musashi!
무사시! 뭔 짓을!
Musashi! What are you doing!?
죽여라. 죽여라. 죽여라!
Kill. Kill. Kill!
무사시 씨! 정신 차리십시오!
Mr. Musashi! Wake up!
필사의 각오로 무사시를 구하러 온 코지로 앞에 막아선 자는, 무슨! 히미코의 요술에 걸려 살인 병기가 되고 만 무사시였다.
The one to stop Kojirō, who came with a firm resolve to lay down his life to rescue Musashi, was - no way! -
Musashi, who became a murder machine under the magic of Himiko.
코지로 일행은 무사시하고 칼로 싸워야만 하는가?
Is the only choice for Kojirō and others to fight Musashi with swords?
코지로 일행도 위기지만 무사시도 또다시 위기!
Everyone on Kojirō's side is in a crisis, but so is Musashi!
과연 이 결판은 어찌 나는가!
How will this end up!?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
히미코 씨의 요술으로 코지로 일행하고 싸운 나.
I fought Kojirō and others because of the magic of Ms. Himiko.
역시 히미코 씨는 나쁜 사람이오.
Ms. Himiko really is a bad person-dasu.
그래도 더 나쁜 건 그 한조이오!
But even worse is that Hanzo-dasu!
놈도 참, 거대한 미사일을 사츠마니아에 들이박을 작정이오!
That guy is trying to smash a huge missile into Satsumania-dasu!
이대로라면 사츠마니아가 전멸하고 마오!
Satsumania will be annihilated at this rate-dasu!
다음 이야기! 시라누이 최후의 음모이오
Next story! The Last Conspiracy of Shiranui
질풍노도의 대폭발이오!
It's a stormy big explosion-dasu!
다음 이야기
시라누이 최후의
음모이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
The Last Conspiracy
of Shiranui
Look forwards for it!